[Music]
Good evening and good the everybody great you'll be with
you again welcome to episode 20 of
the Ask Abhijeet show so we are completing four
weeks today so before I begin I would like you
thank you all from the bottom of my heart
thank you for your viewership thank you for all the
comments thank you for your questions I
really appreciated very much and it would have been
possible without you also thank you very much
and before I begin
and announcement so this this channel list you keep
evolving it needs you keep changing
and I want you keep providing you more
and more value in the form of different
ways of giving you knowledge so I would like you
resume creating long form
documentary style videos of you have been
saying date there I need you to go back
you creating videos like I meet for
Ching's Khan the same change kind
refuge you in India so  I want you to go back and
start doing this again because certain questions, certain
topic
details, so I would like to start doing this again, so I would like to
eventually
start creating such long-form
videos this week, so what I'm going to do is
focus more on this from the
next pic, so what I'm going to do is date. I need
time, I'm going to have to read this,
change the schedule of this show, so in the past nine weeks I've been
doing five shows this
week, so from next week onwards, this
coming week onwards, I will be doing three
live shows for this week, so what I'm going to do is change the schedule. I'm
making this, so there will be three live shows for this
week. I will publish due tomorrow, so I'm not going to ever stop
making these, I really
enjoyed doing this, I enjoy being
interesting with you, I enjoy having this
conversation with you and interesting
with you live and I've shot clips.  that I am
releasing will keep on coming everyday one few
clips birthday so you will keep getting
new content from on this channel everyday and like as well
three live streams this week today
always so there was going to be watch this coming
week onwards so that's it for
dance and now let's get after it today is the
most popular topic Indian
history so let's start with question
number one today there are some
interesting topics in some controversial
topics is well so let's start with
question number one so this is about another
video that I released in which I have
spoken about India
partition date India wants partition with the
people of India want to partition with the
desire partition and I said that India does not want to
partition and there should have been another
reference about this matter so many people have
written in you and this is I am
showing you couple of comments date  Represent
what respect people also been saying so
this date was an referendum d 1946 assembly
election fourth completely on one point and
which in d of creation of Pakistan for d
Muslim League d turn of was very high and
lots of Muslim Pakistan were it inside
comment like tha ishnan more de 90% of
Muslim voted for d creation of
Pakistan and 46 provincial election
so ho can you say de waise no refer and so I hear
you gas and thank you for asking these
questions unless you ask me questions Vi will not have this
conversation so if you full
I am rang you need to express yourself
today you are doing thoughts only Vi very Vi can take this
forward so thank you for asking this
and let me explain what I mean
Okay so no referendum but you gas se hed was an re let's
understand of you things
about democracy which Vi are not talk in
over  education system
rule no one and election date is held
under foreign occupation it neither free nor is it it far
nine is it democratic it is
illegitimate and null and wide imagine if there was an
election in
France during the not see German
occupation of France during the second
world war when France was liberated do you think they continue with the
assembly or what ever the result of the
elections world no
and wide right because date election was held
under not see Germany i min ho can
you consider date election to village in it in
election in Tibet today in Chinese your
brother debate would you considered you be
legitimate election
occupation so ho do you and begin you
consider in election held under British
occupation you be an election of free
election and democratic election ho ho do
you think and thoughts an case it is because over
education system teacher what democracy truly means right so this
election in  1946 was
held under foreign occupation it was
held under British rule you legitimize this they
rule over India and you gave India the last
basically cool glass before leave so that
date was and illegitimate
election it was naidar free no fer not
democratic it was under foreign occupation thats point no one point no one is let's take a look at it same right
so let me share my screen with you so let me share one of these a her
Vi go so
this is an article written by an lady ko Roopa
Subrahmanya the title of the article does matter
Okay but here are some interesting
steps let me make it big so
you can see it properly
so this article is dated the 1946 elections
based on the six scales all of the 1935
Government of India Act head on limited
French choice which me is dated only a small
percentage of adults dos with  People with money and
property were eligible to vote. In fact,
only 3% of the population could vote for the
Central Assembly and only 13% could vote
for the Provincial Assemblies.
Only 30 million people could vote in
assembly elections out of a total adult
population of 120 million. Do you see this? This is what I mean
by
election data. It is not free. Or else there were
120 million adults in India who should have been allowed to
vote, but only less than 30
million were actually allowed.
So it is not a representative election. It did
not represent the will of the true
population of India. Point number two, this
election and four, it was a fabricated
election right and here, point number three,
and election is not a reference. There is a big
difference between an election in reference
and election, where voters elect
representatives, though an election and
referendum is a direct one.  Vote it is win
when and any electorate is ask you to
accept or reject a single proposal and
issue and question both have a
vote but a reference number is not
only election and election is not a
reference separate things and referendum is about only one question
thoughts it you cannot conserve and election
you can be a referendum and interpret its
results as the result of a reference
number date is absolutely acceptable
in democracy if you have to understand what
democracy is and this is ho the 1946 election the
so called 1946 election was
completely legitimate because it was held under or
under foreign occupation it was not
represented by any stretch of the
imagination of the people of India and
thirdly it was not a referendum it was an
election for seats in the legislature
and that's my point  stands but
India was partitioned illegally illegally
by the British they had no business
partitioning India their only business is to
back up and leave and let the Indians
decide what is the future of the
country and date future should have been
decided by a referendum in a free and free
election free referendum in free India
not under British rotation so date is date
my friends please understand
date
Okay question number 2
so Lakshmi ask after Tipu Sultan did the
British rule the warriors back on the
throne of Mysore then you explain the
history behind this and it looks like same kind
of agreement just you sustain
extra light upon it so this body
small family small dynasty who were the owners of
the Vijayanagar Empire the Vijayanagar
Empire was creativity destroy key
foreign investment right Vi no date and then
eventually the British took over the region
and date so after Tipu Sultan was
defeated by foreign powers  Installed in
body
Vi have to understand one thing very
clearly my friends you have a lot of so
called royal families in India today right the
descendants of royal families were the
descendants of the princely status of
India let us understand one thing very clearly the
real royal families and
dynasties of India the genuine legitimate
royal families and dynasties were all whited
out in 1857
royal family is dated Vi have today after 19
after 1857 were puppets that the British
installed on their thrones when they
organized India and took control over the country
some of the Indians are definitely the descendants
of the originalize which you are with the British
so which men are there and these are collaborators huge
you collaborate with the British
against the Indian interest what allowed
you remain on done and dose of what the
British RBI doubted and replaced
perfects so in essence every single royal
family date you have today so cool royal
families are d descendants of their puppets
and collaborators and I am sorry you say d
word
and d includes every other royal family
okay so d true patriots d true
freedom fighters d true royal families of
chat for india d great laxmi bai is and me
ideal there are all wide out their
positions in carted back to england
and puppets for place in in d loo so that what happened so that what
Vi are you
understand both are not royal families are
puppets and kalaboratories th which is and
word
okay and interesting question nine so
Mr Rahul Raj
Mysore Palace of India
let me explain d context i have
released and short clip of an answer d they are there
no royal palace in
India and I said date through India
history India's kings have dear tu a
religious code of conduct very in they cannot
mass luxuries and wealth they have tu
basically serve there  only the highest
morality is you serve the kingdom and the
people and not you enrich and that's why he always lived in Hubli
and he never lived a
luxurious life style so many people have given
me examples of where I am mistaken where I am true want
you to be wrong so this is one
gentleman who is this date the
Mysore Palace of India where the king is an
Hindu il ol this is an joke and what
about Rajasthan which is full of forts
okay so that's when I will give you
example
empty Vi have palace in Vadodara Laxmi
Vilas Palace
what about the Rajasthani palace which are actually
forts
Vijay se episodes like me like this make me doubt all
of the episodes hope
you get a chance to visit Hampi Rajasthan etc ceterases
in India
right good okay good gaadi is not less than
palace etc
so these are goods which Dheeraj would like you
interpreter palace okay
Mysore Palace  andar example
discounting a handful of british
occupation era palaces built by perfect
kings there are no royal palaces in india sprite
countless kingdoms dynasties is an
empire serving flourished over nearly
10000 years of india's archaeological
history wahi ise this so date by the way d
question so i have clearly said date there are
of you british occupation era palaces is
built by perfect kings so d pe palace
and mysore is one of the solid british
occupation era palaces d palace in vadodara
and baroda is again british occupation ise
d palace and this rajasthan
hum page and monument architecture it is one of the
most prosperous empires in
india everything scale but there is no
royal palace then you are mistaken sir there is
no royal palace
rajasthani forts they have to understand
d difference between fort and ab royal
palace ab fort ise an town dat is surrounded dat k a
wall to keep occupiers and
invaders out it is in every town which is
surrounded by all around nine if that every town is built
on a luxurious scale it
means that india was very prosperous in the past it is
not a royal palace it is a place where
everybody including the king and the
commoners and the soldiers everybody would be accommodated with
in the big Rajasthan
forts there are couple of palaces is yes those are
British occupation era palace is please understand
the difference between a palace
and a fort and please understand the difference
between the British occupation era
and the previous 10000 years of India
history so my point stands that with very very few
acceptances there are
no royal palaces in India though out the 10000
year old history of India Indian
kings have always had a religious code of
conduct very in their only duty is to assure the
prosperity of the kingdom and
the people they have  never live luxury slide
as you can see this anywhere in d country there are
no royal palaces is except for d once
i just poke about and d force and
d goods are not before sis r fortifications
very which 1000 built
on an earlier shell scale it only me d
indias very prosperous in dat era
so i hope to clarify this matter
india you learned knowledge and wisdom and was d
company by philosophers and d battle of d
space never happened today he did not have any
intention you are in with india and that is
sikandar so popular this is
d book it's very good very nice little
book by break up i am
going to d very last page of the
book and d very last paragraph let me
read out d court let me read out his
last one paragraph summary of sikandar
extraordinary energy of his genius
two vi condom d selfish and cruel ends tu which
his life was d voted he was
Simply a robber but he is a robber on some vast
scale of mankind and contemplating this
career have generally lost side of the
wicketnce of this crime
of the enormous magnitude of the scale on which
they are perfectly treated this is the truth
about sikandar the great it is
not me who is saying this it is a breakup
about you can buy this book it is very
extensive book in an very nice summary
of this his career so in brief sikandar was
no philosopher he is simply a robber who
committed robbery and theft and crime
normals almost continent level scale thoughts what
sikandar was so I hope that answers this question it is a
good question
and you broad this up and I hope that
answers questions
Okay this is by Rahul Raghunath Rahul Rangana
sorry Rahul Ranganath
Gandhi really they support trade in our
text books acting and whenever  Leader
South African Gandhi which tells you some strange
thoughts on Gandhi in general
book it's called d South Africa
in Gandhiji's life and actions and
activities and clear in South Africa right here in
South Africa for I think this
goes in date and it references Gandhi on
writings so it goes to d very hard of
d matter if you can look from d
writings on d back of d book I think
you can read it so let me read it if you like this is
Mohan Das Gandhi who wrote in 1920 as an
Indian he cooperated with d British
government more than i have for an unbroken
period of 29 years of public life i put
my life in parallel four times for d case
of d empire this is what Mr.
Mohan Das Gandhi wrote in 1920 this is what he
wrote it is still available in d public
domain if you know what you look for it will show
you some more interesting tidbits from
mr. Gandhi's life from this book and
there  About her to her one
example of Mr. Gandhi
Mr. Mohan Goss Gandhi
served as a gentleman Major in the British
Army during the Boer War in South
Africa
1899 to 1902 Okay that point number when
secondly Mr. Gandhi recruited Indian to
fight and fought for Britain in World
War I right let me show you some more truth
about Mr. Gandhi
Mr. Gandhi was a British to allow
Indian to fight for British in the Boer
War in South Africa he shot to give Indian the
opportunity of an third training for
actual warfare so Mr.
Gandhi was a Royal servant of the
British Empire he encouraged Indian to
fight for Britain during World War I when he actually went to
village and from village to village trying to
recruit Indian to fight
for British Empire during
World War I when he became the Under
Secretary of State for India begging him to
accept
non violence against British and here is
evidence this is Mr. Gandhi on later the
afford later Vi beg you  Offer service to you d
authority and Mr. Gandhi speaks about
sharing d responsibilities of membership
of this great umpire so these are sam
fact sam small facts about mistake
gandhi just a few among very
mr gandhi writings his
volume in writings are all available in d
public domain i would encourage you to check d
amount there rather i open se so these are d
fact in d fact speak for dem sales i have i don't have u give
my opinion about
d matter i would like u every
right i have show me sam fact you can look it all up
yourself you can take a look d
book and buy d book online if available online
and sir but better just
look up gandhi mr
gandhi on writings they are all available
online for free right and just go through d if
you have d time and and you will find
very interesting facts d image from there so tha all
about mister mohandas
gandhi m mahatma  Gandhi
Okay Akash Akash Ask Jinnah and the British Who Can Be
Held Responsible for Breaking
India
Jinnah was an tool Mohandas Gandhi was an
tool The British had a long term
objective there on one alive they had a very
clear exit plan for existing
out of India when India became poor
and you are miserable you extract anything more
from right there is nothing left you
extract from India India GDP
crashed you less than 2% of the world GDP
India's life expectancy was around 30
and less than 30 but the time the British
left India that way those thoughts were
desperately poor and destitute India became
hands of the British of the
British right and leave just wanted to leave the country but they wanted to steal the region because they still had
interest in the Gulf right and they wanted
on part of India to be on the sides so that is what they
wanted to break India in couple
of like two or three pieces and  Thoughts what they
achieved via Mr Jinnah so Mr
Jinnah by the way I am really tool by no
men trying to pit Mr Jinnah
for his crimes against his nation and
against his conscience because in this is only
career he is very much and nationalist you are very
much a secularist true
secularist not a fake one like d
people be have today because true nationalist he
fight for Hindu Muslim unity 44 India when you was
in London you was a true
nationalist true freedom fighter and later he
betrayed his own conscience you be tread on
people be treated on nation so I am by no
men trying to pit Mr Jinnah for his
monument crimes specially what it did
in 94 direct action they in all debt but on
d British in d hands of d British
only dandiya hai not Dandi else you do it right
so I hold d British responsible for
breaking India and d responsibility
Also with Mr Jinnah and Mr Gandhi
and Mr Nehru and every respectable leader every
respectable major significant leader in the Indian
National Congress they are all responsible but the poput her the
puppet masters with the
British and these people you are British
collaborators
Thailand and see a large portion of
animalism in Buddhism I wonder if it
goes for Hinduism also animism the is the
believe that every object has a certain
divine essence in it in
spiritual essence it there is divinity in
everything there is divinity and in these
animate objects like rocks and stones they
give this divinity increase and forest and there is
divinity in animals and man and woman
and children so everything has divine
essence with in it and this is what is
called animism in English so
Buddhism yes it has elements of animism
and Buddhism image out of Hinduism
Hinduism  This is very much part of
Hindus believe it there is divinity in
everything yes and many folk practices it is
part of Hinduism Hinduism is very
plural culture it is not a religion in the
western sense it is a culture right it is a
civilization
you can be or not stick in Hinduism you
can be a join you can be a Buddhist
you can be six this is all Hinduism there are many
schools of thought there are
philosophical schools of believe in Hinduism which are very same
times very much it has differences
with each other and they also have great differences and
common so Buddhism and joinism are two of these so it is
Sikhism so it is Charbagh so it is
Mimamsa so it is Vedanta and so are Yoga
and Sankhya
right worship
nature worship part of Hinduism very much so on see
your question in short and amazing very much
part of it say where is it  Part
of this is right Okay
next question
today so region Hindi language in
corporate some Arabic and Persian words is very region same
people in Southern India
find it so difficult to understand
Hindi because they are very more comfortable with
Sanskrit it is very much a part of every
language in India Sanskrit vocabulary is
part of every language in India no matter where
you are right
and it is this Arabic
language it is
very close you Hindi subject Chand
in Hindi in Sanskrit discharge Chand in
Arabic right and I can give you lots of
different examples like that so if you
understand any language that is there
from Sanskrit any Prakriti language it is very similar
for you you learn Persian because it is
essentially part of the same
language family and if you are passing through
living in hostel there couple of Iranian
students there and there pick up Hindi
fluent Hindi matter of months like this
Rasta it is
you learn Kashmiri for example and any
other Indian language that is it is
so personal or Persian is very much part
of the Indo Iranian language family is
almost like any Indian language it is
likeli more distant but it is not hard to
pick up at all Arabic on the other and tired
different language from any entirely different
language right and persons have by
force you adopt and you or you adopt the
Arabic script with some modifications so that appears that person is
close to
Arabic by it is not I am  Sir Arabic loan
words inside person you bikers of d
history dat Iran has head for d pass
thousand news it was under occupation
and it haj bin med you absorbed Arabic culture
and and great deal of d Arabic life so there must be I am
sir a great deal of Arabic
loan words in the for c language I have
not studied this language but I understand
the linguistic
aspect of d language phamili d red
belongs to you so very different language
extremely different but these are both
present in sir defining quantity in
Hindi because of d Turkish occupation of
India which also plot in Arabic portion in
fluence right so dat is d region same Vi
unfortunately you so much for and loan words
today it is not because of award choice because of because of
d de history dat over country his hand
over d battered future century
same cold the Indian National Army late by
Subhash Chandra Bose did not achieve its objective what were the major
problems  In our
stomach it's a very common and very old
cliche but it's very true and the army
needs logistical supply chain in order to
succeed you need an
NDTV fire and you need food unit water
unit supply change logistics is what
sustains the fighting force nine subhash chandra bose did not have
access to you great deal of
resources it was
abbreviation and food and all debt
and
fighting basically award
in the jungle
right so it was an ill occupied army it was
shot and fans it was shot on food it was
shot on all kids of supply it's the only
thing is country courage and their blood so mujhe khoon do main tumhe
aazadi dunga sir so there was what what could they be
fighting so this is the reason why
subhash bose and the ian could not achieve their
objective military there up against the enemy
allied forces right the british
indian army the americans this was a very
professional armed fighting force right very
well supplied because no short  further of funds
and food and ammunition and water and anything right and there is no
shortage of
troops is well and in
head limited troops which are all
taken out of the Japanese love
piyurablues award date they have taken from
d British Indian Army so that was the same this
army could not achieve its objective it was always against it it was fighting against
encourable all it was
basically a suicide mission and d read it
for d law of their country and c ho d ho d
treated after independence right so that's
India for you my friends is d
Nehru Vi and resume for you they dislike anybody who
for d British using violent
men
so in brief that was the same the same the I N A and d
great Subhash Chandra Bose could not achieve d
objectives military they unfortunately
by and accident of history head you pick
head you go on d wrong side d side d
ended up losing because d logic was dat my
Enemies are enemies my friend so the
Japanese and the Germans were fighting the
British at that time know what the Japanese
in British what the chapter Germans did not doing at that
time it is only after the
war ended the people came to know of the
Japanese what they what the nations what up to and
what the Japanese in
various parts of China so Subhash Bose
basically was an pragmatic
his country by other men necessary and dated
it the right approach unfortunately he and it up
on his side lost the war and he was
basically very short of every supply you can imagine he was
short of troops and short of everything else
logistics
and that's why he did not succeed in the
Indian Navy he did not succeed
Okay this is my
Marathas were just readers Shivaji
matriculate in Karnataka were
killed regarding there and looted the temple so don't think then he was same sort
of savior
about  Whatever would go in other kingdoms and
if the night you give simply burn the crops of the
farmers they will not differ from the other
kingdom so wanted you to expand for their own use.
Shivaji yes Shivaji Maharaj did loot Surat you
times Surat was
occupied by Mughals but the argument is right
and what Shivaji did what the great
Shivaji did he looted the Mughal treasury
in Surat and looted this will be the merchants who are
making the Mughals prosperous it is
not touch any single civilian haj gona tell you this I am
sir you are not going to tell us this date right you are not going to write this date in the
comments and I know I am well educated people who say
date c wajji Maharaj was a bad
person because you looted Surat
ameen come on he did not touch any single
civilian and house looted the Mughals
the merchants who are making the Mughals prosperous
and there is perfectly justified alright
secondly the Marathas constantly rated Bengal
and yesterday in Hindus this again is communist
propaganda thoughts for the communication
writing ever science independence the Mughals
trying to free bungalows
from this
date
basically necessary  Necessity
warfare and rates in the Bengali territory which is
occupied by the Turks there would be
battles in Bengali terms did employ
Hindu soldiers right dodges would get killed in
the warfare but once again the civilians did not touch
and nothing was burnt this is all
communist lies which have been fabricated
after independence
and the moment
Paratha leadership came to know about this those people gave back to
the Sringeri Math and this is the
fact look it up online these are all
communist lies which are the communist structures which have been
spreading the false
acquisitions against the Marathis in order to
make the Marathis look after the Marathis were always
acted ethically according to the
principles according to the ethics and
morality of Indian warfare they never touched
civilians and on the one hand of chance that all this happened the
criminals were punished and the
positions were returned  You did string
so when exception is not the rule yes when such thing
happened and action was taken from
play against it alright
so basically everything
Mughal had influence because of Chhatrapati
Shivaji Maharaj to a great extent yes but if
Shivaji Maharaj was not
good what he achieved it mean it had
influence to a greater extent in Southern India you fell under influence to a
greater extent and after the
great Shivaji his success expanded the
mother empire and more and these are
things
of the invaders and also because this is very far away
country 16 so its a combination of
facts and factors but yes the Marathis and
the great Shivaji did have a significant
role to play in protecting the southern
part of India than
more number of classical dance forms
exist in South India Carnatic music
is much more elaborate in Hindustani
classical music is it possible
It's an very interesting question so
first one has a small collection of Carnatic music is
not much elaborate d Hindustani
classical music I would not be a
musician right Okay I am also
understand Indian classical music and
d rhas and all dat right I so or I will not
going to dat basically Carnatic music
and Hindustani music have music with
share
classified under different name in d North so that point no one has no two yes more
classical dance forms exist in Southern
India compared to nine in India in
Northern India you only have one dance
form which is Kathak which is
not one of my favourite dance
forms by other men but in Southern India
and Eastern India you have more dance
forms that have survived so yes I think it is very very
logical what you are saying that
dance forms in d Northern
part of India have been lost during
d talking rule it is very much
possible yes wile so d Indian  Once did get
saved
udissi is one of the most beautiful and
most interesting dance forms in india that was
saved in north east india was from
manipuri in assam survived two
different dance forms manipuri is one of the
classical dance forms of indian
classical dance you know the major dance forms
and kuchipudi
so yes it looks like southern india did it prosper
culturally continue to prosper because there is way lesser
turkish influence
in india right and its interesting note that in some of the
dance forms in south east
asia like apsara dance and aadar dance and
cambodia and thailand and burma et
cetera are greatly influenced by southern
indian classical dance forms its very
interesting and manipuri classical dance is similar to the
dance forms that you have in
myanmar burma and also sam outside
thailand and other parts of asia is the most
very fascinating topic of research but
unfortunately nobadi is  Doing research
right so it's something that should be looked at it's an
very fascinating topic I think you are absolutely right it is
most likely a
case that there are more dance forms that
existed in India which have been
ruled by Turks and
some ancient martial arts are still prevalent in
India
so very interesting question is did
the
Padmanabhaswamy temple in
the world is the richest temple or structure and
gold and gems world from what Vi no
swamy temple in kerala is the world's
richest religious
monument and temple run worship it is
estimated that it contains more than one
trillion dollars worth of gold and jewellery
right and there are number of world's
temples underground which is this the supreme court
of judiciary of india has first the
temple authority is too open and I think some quote I
think the local kerala high court and something had
ordered the state government to
take position of  All this wealth and I
think the Supreme Court is reversing the
decision for nine so it is again back in the depths
of the Travancore Royal Family
so it is
incredibly
rich place and the wealth of this bin
founder is mind boggling it is
estimated to be over 1 trillion dollars
and more in worth in value so there are gold
coins from the Roman era lots
of gold coins from the Roman era
from Rome which have been built by the founder of bin
coins found from Mesopotamia and
Greece gold coins and diamonds there are like that there are the
size of an overgrown thumb
and so much more it is an
incredible amount of ancient wealth and it is
clearly something that has been donated to this
temple by Devotis over thousands of years because this temple is mentioned
in this
Sangam literature for about 300 years in Tamil
Sangam literature from around 300 AD which
Place it was which time it was said to be
made out of solid gold
roof was made out of solid gold that would have been it was about
1.5
thousand years ago so it seems that there was
bin donation coming
in this temple for thousands of beers and
kings possibly from Mesopotamia and
Greece they may have made sh and from Rome
they may have made substantial donation to the
temple so there is a very ancient story here this
temple science you may be thousands of
beers old right and it is fabulously
wealthy and the problem is this that this wealth should not be
missepropreated by the state
government or other government it belongs to the temple
and you can only right so it has to remain there it
cannot be missed
for whatever this is the
problem in India that
temples the wealth of the temple is always
tolled in the government  This is the way India is one of the
most Hindu for most nations in the
world because we are discriminated against
by law and by the constitution
so this is the example only it is the
temple in
my far end may be one of the oldest is well so interesting very interesting
question
Okay right Nepal Prime Minister Yoga
originated from Nepal and not India do we have any
proof from where did yoga
and jinn net
so oldest evidence of your god date we have anywhere in the
world are little statues
from the saptasinduri ball so called
Harappan and Indus Valley civilization era of
India this Saraswati civilization so you get this little
statue of there of humanoid of
human beings human figures engaged and
various yugapose it bc I can put up
on the internet let me Harappan era
interesting let me tree and tree you
pain stretchulation
let me share my screen
this is the screen
over ancient civilization of  Individuals
of people, men and women who are
engaged in various yogis today, you can see this and
yogi poses date. Vi are steel family
so this is oldest non-depiction of yoga anywhere in the
non-universe
so this is clean by Mr. Oli it is more I am
sorry to say it is
laughable he is just making a fool of
himself the prime minister of Nepal
and it is just a
political tool to you need India because he is
basically porn in the hands of Chinese
mister only so yoga originated in the sapta
Sindhu region or me also but this is where
Vi are found the oldest events so based
on the evidence based on the data. Vi can see
date the oldest non-evidence is from the
Sindhu region from the Saraswati wali Indus
wali region so it is not from the region of Nepal called
Nepal which is over by
part of India it is a separate kingdom
in the region of ₹80000  Only in the mid 18th century
only and it's only an accident of history
date country right now it is very much part
of India and Nepal is people over on people
and there is an region there right
you can come and live in India and work in
India they don't need bizas there are no
controls you can they can come in live here
and so can Indian go in live in Nepal
because Vi are se people d se culture d se
ethnicity d se civilization for thousands
of this statement it just mint you need
India it basically basically be laugh laugh that all it deserves
Okay this is Shashwat Singh who asked him is it
called Adam's bridge he did d name it
back I assume your referring which is called Adam's
bridge right so let
me share something interesting with you
call the
most ancient
example of monument architecture in the
world there called it Adam's bridge
Sri Lanka
it is known as Shripad
print so Hindu considered you be d
footprint  of Lord Hanuman and Lord Shiva
and d Buddhist considered to be d
footprint of Lord Buddha so dat local name
in sinhalese and tamil and sanskrit it is
sripada which means d secret food print
but d English occupier d British
occupiers have named Adam speak and that what
wikipedia reverse it refers to it is
and similarly every atlas and every
website online refers to d Ramas for
further Adams bridge you put Adam everywhere
for same region it's a form of culture
and imposition it's a form of trying to establish
cultural premasi it's a tree
it's a form of its its means of
trying to give great Indian culture which
sri lanka culture is also actually
Indian culture right so this is what they have been trying to do ever
science the occupied this this
civilization there are been trying to rename
things and there are lots of d example where there are
trees you rename things right  So the
great Sagar Mata became Mount Everest
Sagarmatha and and Chaumul Ma in Tibetan
date Vi can Mount Everest Vadodara become
Baroda
Jagannath become Jagannath the Ganga become Gangesh
the Sindhu become the Indus and so on and so
for I get I am
sir
examples so there without trying to rename everything
and unfortunately and after
independence Vi have kept on using doses strange
Vi don't need you call it Adam's bridge Vi should just
call an Adam's bridge so which is the
correct name was all
Atul ask if Sanskrit
same does it have so many scripts wide
Vi don't find scripts in other
languages ​​found world wide this is a
brilliant observation sir there is
no language
and European languages ​​all Islamic
languages ​​have the Cyrillic script Arabic
Indian have multitude of very closely
related scripts 14 languages
it is me around for thousands of offers and
thoughts same  it different eras in history
prevailed for several centuries so during that
period sanskrit is in the brahmi
script letter on other strips
scripts image so sanskrit it's
van of thouse today it is written in the de
vaganik script you can write
sanskrit in the tibetan script today well
and you can write sanskrit in the mongol
svayambhu script is well so sanskrit
written date is same and it is the oldest
language no to human kind no sumirian is
not
and language old and sanskrit is my
far the oldest language no to human
kind
and date is same because it's been around
4000 years it is built in so many
different lands in so many different
scripts
one script is hardly one vehicle was this
mant to carry one language one vehicle convey
concave change is long today it is suitable
for carrying one script one vehicle is
acceptable right so sanskrit it's been
written in so many different scripts very very good question very good okay i
think about  Selected in d so
let's take up a few let's take up a
lot of your
life questions let's take a look at it what
you are asking
alright is
not Indian history sir
Vi support Shivaji Maharaj
scholar
no scholar he is
Ashoka overrated I don't think he is
overrated but his Rangali portrait his
portrait is a saint actually the
destruction he caused on Kalinga in the
Kalinga war there is no conversion first of all
you other dharmic religion you just
started practicing in d religion secondly he started practicing d
tenis of
Buddhism
before d Kalinga war tok place so he was already a
Buddhist sonu se when he was
thou war with Kalinga and how so many karnas there and the
fact is d thik killed so many people because deh oppoz dem he persecuted d
Ajivi people he also killed
d Jains he also killed great
members of his family in
order to securities hold on d throne
and so on so he was an brutal tairnet
and it is truly true people in India
and like you glorify right so Ashoka well actually
one of the worst kings in India
not to be surprised defended an palace from the
reign of his
capital city Pataliputra right so so
thoughts about Ashoka sir
North Sentinel Island in India its a
small island which is home to one of the
last
unconducted morrowless uncontested
ancient human populations on the world
on earth so it's basically a population that
migrated out of Africa
on this island and there are people living there every
science they are still basically in the
stone age they may not be immune to any of the
decision you right so the government of
India thankfully I am glad has decided to
leave the island and the government decided to
prohibit any kind of contact with this
people so recently some American
missionaries there you see this
Bible is in hand and I  was shot today
not retrieving his body and by not
prosecuting this
person because he is not modern
[music]
so that is essentially what it is it is an de
facto autonomous territory under
India's protection it is un protected it is
part of Indian territory but we are
treating it as a de facto autonomous territory which will not be
interfered with so I think it is a good thing he has no one to be able to climb the
top of Mount Kailash is it just another
problem or is there more to the story of the
mountain it is secret to three different
cultural religious practices it is set in
Hinduism, Buddhism, Jainism and the fourth one is
Tibetan born religion
it is a secret mountain it is considered to be the
center of the world it is considered to be about the
great Lord Shiva it is a
secularism you and
climbing the mountain and the Chinese have
the good  it is a secularism you think of climbing it tom jones did nepal not choose you to become part of india if india is so great so tom jons requested
india's prime minister
shri nehru to allow nepal to rejoin india in 1950 this is
well documented you can
look at online so dry so the king of nepal wanted nepal to become
part of india again he wanted nepal to rejoin india it is only because of the decision
of over prime minister of india
prime minister shri the great jawaharlal
nehru that nepal was able to
reintegrate india mr nehru refused
this request  he said he did not want
Nepal to be part of India
so yes India is great Nepal did want to
rule India it was the Indian prime
minister who prevented them from
joining India
what else do Vi have what else do
Vi help some
interesting questions let me find some what about
inequality in temple entry
o what exactly do you mean by this term
not sir a temple is a
religious place i think they can
set some rules as per there is
India's millennium old culture and
religion i think that gets supreme
so i don't see anything wrong with temple
setting they are on rules
ok some more questions Kailash again
culture is different because it was a separate
country from ancient times there was no
country sir in the past its nation state
history is a very recent idea it dates back to the
third of westfaliya just two three
centuries ago they had no nation status in
the
Sri Lanka is very much part
of Indian civilization it is very much
part of Indian culture and if you look at
Sri Lanka's founder history the
founder of the great lord Kumar the great
prince Kumar came from India and settled
in Srilanka versus followers in these days the
ancestors of today in Hinduism and
Sinhalese is very much an Prakrit derived
language it is closest to I think
Marathi in India so there is nothing separate
about Sri Lanka Vi do recognize the
sovereignty and independence of Sri Lanka
Vi agree it is independent country today
but it should have been part of India after
independence what happened Vi don't have
other designs territorial designs on
Sri Lanka
best of the people of Sri Lanka whoever on people from Nepal
so it was never separate country and separate
culture anything is separate from ethnicity, culture
and civilization vi dot
by nuclear
civilization that happened  During the
Mahabharata era one sentence answer no I do
not use Wikipedia
yes I do not fund Wikipedia I agree
Wikipedia so if I do
show you Wikipedia from time to time it is only
for convenience it is not because I
endorse
Wikipedia and believe in its accuracy it is entirely it is to a very
great
extent in accurate I have seen this on my
location myself so agree with its
statement yes
central government I
think they have elected the government so do
watch best for the country not
changing any single word in our
history text books I remember the
right honourable Mr the right honourable
minister what is his name Mr Prakash
Javadekar who very proudly boasted that Vi have not changed any
single word in our
history text books
saying that very proudly Vi have done nothing
great minister for doing nothing so
Mr Javed Dekar unfortunately I
regret that he was a failure is the
minister in charge of  This matter and who ever is the
current minister right now again he
basically doesn't know anything about this so I must say date is very
disappointing
okay what else do they have is
Tamil the oldest or Sanskrit
evidence date we have
found Sanskrit d evidence of
Sanskrit it is older the evidence for
Tamil d evidence
for Sanskrit is from an region that was
conquered and settled in ancient India
about free and a half of 4 thousand years ago it is
in present day Syria and
Anatolia it is the Mitanni kingdom which is
very find the oldest evidence of written
Sanskrit so this is an out of India
migration
okay so it's about three and a half or 4000 years old the
Mitanni and the Hittites so that was very
fine it the oldest evidence for Tamil is
from Sangam literature which goes back to around
400 or 500 AD the oldest okay so from
This events from hard evidence
Vi have one that is to be seen in sensitive Sanskrit is the
oldest but this does not mean that
Tamil may not also be old further back but it may also be
possible that
both languages ​​are free from this evidence but it is very
much
possible because in Rig Veda Vi have one
sage Agastya who is one of the authors of
some of the verses in the Vedas and he is
considered to be the father of Tamil language and
he is the person who wrote the first grammar
of Tamil language so according to considering this fact these
events would most likely be factually
correct that
Tamil and Sanskrit are equally old but this
evidence was Vi have today and today if you go only for this evidence it looks older so it is not matter that if you go only
for this evidence it looks older so it is not matter that if
you go only for this then Vi need more
data about this so
Evidence is going to change and over
understanding of this matter because of change
but please understand my friends this is
not a competition these are both of our
greatest language and Vi must o  Nar dem
equally to Daksh Daksh about this
Okay what is
community of
history
white wash products
and it's because
[music]
invasion after invasion from the trucks and
they prevent in the territories from
occupying the enter of North East
India so the important contribution to
safeguarding and certain part of the country
[music] who has
contributed to the country
text books same the contribution of the
Jat note
of history
and homes and one of this I think there are one of the very
significant
dynasty is in India they have
contributed a great deal to this
country in the form of defence in the form
of culture well so I would like you to see all of these
dynasty is that date and make and
all of this communication date make India such a
vibrant plural and beautiful place I want you to see
these are all
recognized in India history text
books
Russian is also like Sanskrit because it also come
from Sanskrit you  There are words in
Russian there are exactly two Sanskrit
words and words are derived from
Sanskrit so
linguistics is a very interesting field if you go
deep into this you will find lots
and lots of linkages it will have a sound so yes
Russian is a
European language
okay what else okay
let me take this question same two
modern day historians consider King Vikram
Aditya and Vikram Samvat fake which is around
10 and about it because in modern day
historimselves
date Maharaja Vikramaditya was a legendary
and mythical king not really exist which is absolute
non sense considering date in the ancient
era of Indian history he is named after this
king after this empire so there
trying to white wash these great
historical figures out of Indian history that all it is
completely disagree with this contention date
emperor Vikram Aditya
image of his existence
okay
Please
talk animals
well I have never seen India
temples so as for as
my limited knowledge goes I have not seen
other events of this I do have
evidence of this so you can show it next
time or I will try and look it up from
my knowledge whatever limitations I have never seen
in other events of date if there is any other such thing it means it is there
I have found some
bones of dinosaurs
and try to reconstruct for the animals I have
looked and look like it is well not
dated India is one of the repositories of a
great deal of dinosaurs but they do exist
in India
so if such does exist it may indicate date
over and hence they have found those
dinosaur bones and try to recreate
likeness of the dinosaurs
alright let me take one more question and I think will be done after that
Praveen Mohan video about evidence of
carvings of dinosaurs Okay thank you for
the reference I will I will try and look at that
Shon thank you
Okay what else do they have to do Vi have other
interesting questions only I once it
award
Okay I think Vi are almost done here
Okay this is the final question for today
my friends in one of the article from
school it was mentioned that Hindu kings also built
temples in subducted idols
examples by the way it was mentioned
look d role is not on website that you can really take very
seriously when it comes to Indian
history especially in the treatment of the
topic of Hinduism first of all let me say it
Okay so anything they write about
Hinduism and Indian history you take it
with a tablespoon of salt
secondly it is true so same extent certain
in d king certain Indian kings would
red d kingdoms and when they would
capture and Kankar kingdom they would go to d
greatest temple and take d idol from there
with great respect in reverence and
bring it back to their capital  and install
it in dear temple
so they would never loot a temple or desi
creator temple and some other sort of
secularism and tomorrow they preserve anything they
revealed these temples and there their
idol so much they would same times and conquer one
kingdom just you bring back this great
ideal with its great power back your
kingdom so that is the most
Okay
no Hinduism
what you are referring to is nice
in the rail of facts but a great deal of
distortion also which is being put a
cross by this scroll or what ever it is so
these so thoughts what it is about
Okay do you have anything else will it will
fair experiment it is not
part of Indian history thank you now I am not aware
of other course of d
no on d away of d pad man of d shopping temple I am
not on financial things
sorry
d varna system very complex topic
five minutes of d cup answer I have you
Basically give exposition of this thing you know it's a
very complex topic so I will do it I will do it
definataly but in the future
Okay I think Vi don't for today so gas
thank you so much thank you for all your
questions thank you for your viewership I am very great full like I said
next
week
I will continue releasing d shot
making again long form documentary
style video very heard so tha what you
can look for next week onwards so
tomorrow I will publish d schedule of
next week and I will see you very heard I will see
you next week very heard so thank
you